# **Sarah Cross**

sarah.cross617@gmail.com | 9074339394 | linkedin.com/in/sarah-cross-79098b254

## **SUMMARY**

Recently gained experience working in data solutions as a software engineer intern for the OKC Thunder. Fast learner and flexible team player with creativity, communication, and strong problem-solving skills. Returned to school after 11 years as a stay-at-home mom and military spouse. Currently seeking full-time role as software engineer with opportunities for career growth and development.

# **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

### **BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | AUBURN UNIVERSITY**

Fall 2020-Spring 2023

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with 4.0 GPA
- Ginn College of Engineering Dean's List
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

#### INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

# DATA SOLUTIONS SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN | OKC THUNDER

Spring 2024

- Worked on full stack application using Python with Django, JavaScript, Typescript, and HTML/SCSS with Angular to build out a player evaluation page to production.
- Spearheaded the integration of an NBA player evaluation distribution page into the app, facilitating more insightful player analysis.
- Transformed static player evaluations into sliding scale distributions and visualized data with dynamic D3 charts, enhancing decision-making processes for scouts and coaches.

### **PROGRAMMING PROJECTS**

- Mars Rover iOS app that displays latest images of each of the Mars Rovers: Swift, API calls
- Olo Web Browser with editable browser history: C#, SQL database
- Spam message classifier to predict if message is spam or not: Python, machine learning
- Hospital database query menu: Java, MySQL database

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## SUBSTITUTE TEACHER | FAIRWOOD CHRISTIAN PRESCHOOL

September 2021-February 2023

- Upheld classroom routines to support student environments and maintain consistent schedules.
- Repeatedly requested as substitute teacher based on excellent past referrals and trusted performance.
- SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER | EXCEL CHRISTIAN SCHOOL

April 2019-April 2023

- Developed marketing content for social media with the goal of driving interest and community support.
- Analyzed and reported social media and online marketing campaign results.

# STRENGTHS AND OTHER EXPERIENCE

- Comfortable in Java; experienced in Python, C#, Swift, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML/CSS.
- Experience with Spring Boot, Angular and Django frameworks, git and GitHub, SonarQube, and ZAP.